<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><xml><records><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Rosenblatt, Adam</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The Danger of a single story about forensic humanitarianism</title><secondary-title>Journal of Forensic and Legal Medicine</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Forensic and Legal Medicine</full-title></periodical><pages>75-77</pages><volume>61</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2019</year></dates><publisher>Churchill Livingstone</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.jflm.2018.11.007</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Rosenblatt - 2019 - The Danger of a single story about forensic humanitarianism.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S1752928X18305535</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Since the mid-1980s, forensic scientists have played a crucial role in the international response to mass violence, contributing evidence to war crimes tribunals and identifying bodies to end the tortuous uncertainty of loved ones. Recently, experts at the International Committee for the Red Cross have described these activities using the term “humanitarian forensic action,” applying it from the field's origins in Argentina to the multiple organizations and types of projects that exist today. This article cautions against any account of the history of humanitarian forensic action, or its contemporary landscape, that is so simple and unified. It points to divergent mandates, working methods, and even definitions of humanitarianism, focusing especially on new ways in which forensic scientists are addressing the mass suffering caused by structural violence.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Medina, Eden</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Forensic Identification in the Aftermath of Human Rights Crimes in Chile: A Decentered Computer History</title><secondary-title>Technology and Culture</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Technology and Culture</full-title></periodical><pages>S100-S133</pages><volume>59</volume><issue>4S</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2018</year></dates><publisher>Johns Hopkins University Press</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1353/tech.2018.0151</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Medina - 2018 - Forensic Identification in the Aftermath of Human Rights Crimes in Chile A Decentered Computer History.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://muse.jhu.edu/article/712115</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>As computer historians extend the bounds of what constitutes computer history, they must also take care not to write histories that overstate the importance of these technologies. “Decentering” the computer in computer history provides a way for historians to study the role of computers in more domains without exaggerating their importance. Here I illustrate how the use of a computer system for forensic identification formed part of Chile’s complicated history of truth, justice, and reconciliation in the aftermath of the Pinochet dictatorship. While computers are not, and should not be, the central focus of how we understand processes of truth and reconciliation in history, in this case they illuminate the dynamics of how those working within the Chilean government, including its justice system, have approached Chile’s history of human rights abuses.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Crettol, Monique</author><author>Milner, Lina</author><author>La Rosa, Anne-Marie</author><author>Stockwell, Jill</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Establishing mechanisms to clarify the fate and whereabouts of missing persons: A proposed humanitarian approach</title><secondary-title>International Review of the Red Cross</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Review of the Red Cross</full-title></periodical><pages>589-618</pages><volume>99</volume><issue>905</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1017/S1816383118000309</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Crettol et al. - 2017 - Establishing mechanisms to clarify the fate and whereabouts of missing persons A proposed humanitarian approach.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.cambridge.org/core/product/identifier/S1816383118000309/type/journal_article</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This article examines the different types of mechanisms which can contribute to addressing the issue of the missing, including providing answers on the fate and whereabouts of missing persons. It looks in detail at one approach that the authors have observed in the field. It argues that an approach based on humanitarian objectives which does not look into who is responsible for the disappearance, with proper management of confidential information, could be a powerful instrument for searching for and collecting relevant information on the missing in certain contexts. The article also proposes avenues for further research, with a view to enhancing the global capacity to provide meaningful answers for the missing and their families.&lt;/p&gt;</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Accatino, Daniela</author><author>Collins, Cath</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Truth, Evidence, Truth: The Deployment of Testimony, Archives and Technical Data in Domestic Human Rights Trials</title><secondary-title>Journal of Human Rights Practice</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Human Rights Practice</full-title></periodical><pages>81-100</pages><volume>8</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>archives</keyword><keyword>forensics</keyword><keyword>proof</keyword><keyword>prosecution</keyword><keyword>transitional justice</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>Oxford Academic</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1093/jhuman/huv019</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Accatino, Collins - 2016 - Truth, Evidence, Truth The Deployment of Testimony, Archives and Technical Data in Domestic Human Rights Tria.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://academic.oup.com/jhrp/article-lookup/doi/10.1093/jhuman/huv019</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This article analyses how judicial activity in domestic prosecution of dictatorship-era human rights violations shapes and contributes to the accumulation and verification of archival evidence. In particular, it discusses the ways in which trials challenge the status of existing sources of truth, such as truth commission findings, as well as producing new kinds of information and new sources of doubt about crimes of the recent past. The paper argues that novel 'truth orders' are produced by transitional artifices such as the truth commission and other administrative instances. Trials constitute another such order, with a separate and in some senses more socially established claim to legitimacy. It is in some senses inevitable, therefore, that competing truth claims arise when prosecutions are added to the post-transitional mix. Particular aspects of the technically challenging process of investigating long-ago crimes introduce additional professional considerations. The procedures and protocols applicable to forensic science and police work must be assimilated and evaluated by judges charged with turning old and new data into usable evidence. The particular rules of evidence, probatory value, and standards of proof that judges are mandated by law to apply challenges and transforms, in sometimes unpredictable ways, the social legitimacy or veracity previously attributed to such data. This challenge is particularly significant when the imperative of judicial truth interacts with sources of social truth. The production and diffusion of verdicts in criminal trials affects public perceptions of past and present judicial neutrality and legitimacy, and also alters relatives', survivors' and bystanders' views about past events and present responsibilities. Investigations carried out under written judicial procedure lead, eventually, to the production of a new meta-archive, a repository of tested and validated truth which may reinforce, challenge, complete or utterly discredit previous versions of events.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Collins, Cath</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Transitional Justice ‘From Within’: Police, Forensic and Legal Actors Searching for Chile’s Disappeared</title><secondary-title>Journal of Human Rights Practice</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Human Rights Practice</full-title></periodical><pages>19-39</pages><volume>10</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Chile</keyword><keyword>disappearance</keyword><keyword>forensic science</keyword><keyword>lawyers</keyword><keyword>search and identification</keyword><keyword>transitional justice</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2018</year></dates><publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1093/jhuman/huy003</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Collins - 2018 - Transitional Justice ‘From Within’ Police, Forensic and Legal Actors Searching for Chile’s Disappeared.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://academic.oup.com/jhrp/article/10/1/19/4992282</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This article offers an empirically grounded, practitioner-focused analysis of the present-day search for Chile's dictatorship-era disappeared. It treats this search as a transitional justice process within which rights and duties around truth, justice, reparations, and guarantees of non-repetition are explicitly or implicitly performed and (re)negotiated by, inter alia, state agents. Drawing on close observation of, and ongoing engagement with, the police, forensic, and legal actors who are involved in this search day to day, it provides insights into how these state actors understand their task, and manage related challenges and professional dilemmas. These include divergence in what is meant, and sought, when the terms 'truth' and 'justice' are used; the effect of generational replacement; and the necessary limits of victimcentredness within a criminal justice frame. Finally, the article argues for greater attention to this type of closely observed, supply-side analysis of how, and by whom, states' transitional justice duties are actually carried out. This is important, not least because such routinization of transitional justice functions provides learning opportunities for the field, exposing incompatibilities, gaps or contradictions in or between core transitional justice tenets.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Collins, C.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Human Rights Trials in Chile during and after the 'Pinochet Years'</title><secondary-title>International Journal of Transitional Justice</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>International Journal of Transitional Justice</full-title></periodical><pages>67-86</pages><volume>4</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2010</year></dates><publisher>Oxford University Press (OUP)</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1093/ijtj/ijp023</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Collins - 2010 - Human Rights Trials in Chile during and after the 'Pinochet Years'.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://academic.oup.com/ijtj/article-lookup/doi/10.1093/ijtj/ijp023</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This article reflects on the recent Chilean experience of accountability actions, particularly the attempted prosecution of perpetrators of past human rights violations. While acknowledging the undoubtedly substantial impulse provided by the dramatic October 1998 UK arrest of former dictator Augusto Pinochet, it focuses on domestic actors and drivers in a post-1998 revival of such attempts. The article examines the extent and limitations of recent change in the area of prosecutions in Chile, noting that these have been undertaken at the insistence of private actors rather than the state. It also notes that the self-amnesty law of 1978 is still textually intact despite advances in restricting its application with regards to certain categories of internationally proscribed crimes. Finally, the article examines some explanatory factors for both recent advances and remaining blockages in the Chilean human rights accountability scenario.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Collins, Cath</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Chile a más de dos décadas de justicia de transición</title><secondary-title>Política. Revista de Ciencia Política</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Política. Revista de Ciencia Política</full-title></periodical><pages>79-113</pages><volume>51</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>justicia</keyword><keyword>reparaciones.</keyword><keyword>verdad</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><publisher>Universidad de Chile</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.5354/0719-5338.2013.30160</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Collins - 2013 - Chile a más de dos décadas de justicia de transición.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://revistapolitica.uchile.cl/index.php/RP/article/view/30160</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Este trabajo examina las principales políticas públicas y medidas oficiales en materia de justicia de transición –verdad, justicia, reparaciones y garantías de no repetición– logrados en Chile desde 1990 con respecto a violaciones masivas de los Derecho Humanos cometidas bajo la dictadura cívico-militar de 1973 a 1990. Concluye que el balance actual de avances graduales y aún parciales ha sido el resultado de presiones desde la sociedad civil e inesperadas &amp;#13; ‘irrupciones de la memoria’, más que de una política oficial sistemática de repudio a la violencia política y atención al manejo de su legado</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>CED</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Observaciones finales sobre el informe presentado por Chile en virtud del artículo 29, párrafo 1, de la Convención</title><secondary-title>CED/C/CHL/CO/1</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>CED/C/CHL/CO/1</full-title></periodical><keywords/><dates><year>2019</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://CED - 2019 - Observaciones finales sobre el informe presentado por Chile en virtud del artículo 29, párrafo 1, de la Convención.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://ddhh.minjusticia.gob.cl/media/2020/02/CED-2019.pdf</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>CED</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Principios rectores para la búsqueda de personas desaparecidas</title><secondary-title>CED/C/7</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>CED/C/7</full-title></periodical><keywords/><dates><year>2019</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://CED - 2019 - Principios rectores para la búsqueda de personas desaparecidas.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Book Section">7</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>INDH</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Justicia transicional y reparaciones</title><secondary-title>Informe Anual. Situación de los derechos humanos en Chile</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Informe Anual. Situación de los derechos humanos en Chile</full-title></periodical><pages>189-214</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><pub-location>Santiago de Chile</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://INDH - 2017 - Justicia transicional y reparaciones.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.indh.cl/bb/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/01_Informe-Anual-2017.pdf</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Unpublished Work">37</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Collins, Cath</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Respuestas estatales a la desaparición forzada en Chile: aspectos forenses, policiales y jurídicos</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Collins - 2016 - Respuestas estatales a la desaparición forzada en Chile aspectos forenses, policiales y jurídicos.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>www.derechoshumanos.udp.cl</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Book Section">7</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lira, Elizabeth</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Giusti, Miguel</author><author>Gutiérrez, Gustavo</author><author>Salmón, Elizabeth</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Chile. Desaparición forzada: 1973-2015</title><secondary-title>La verdad nos hace libres. Sobre las relaciones entre filosofía, derechos humanos, religión y universidad</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>La verdad nos hace libres. Sobre las relaciones entre filosofía, derechos humanos, religión y universidad</full-title></periodical><pages>549-573</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><pub-location>Lima</pub-location><publisher>Fondo editorial de la Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú</publisher><isbn>978-612-317-114-8</isbn><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Lira - 2015 - Chile. Desaparición forzada 1973-2015.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>www.fondoeditorial.pucp.edu.pe</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Diseño de cubierta: Gisella Scheuch, sobre la base de la escultura Logos, de Margarita Checa, fotografiada por Alicia Benavides Diagramación, corrección de estilo y cuidado de la edición: Fondo Editorial PUCP Primera edición: junio de 2015 Tiraje: 500 ejemplares Prohibida la reproducción de este libro por cualquier medio, total o parcialmente, sin permiso expreso de los editores. Hecho el Depósito Legal en la Biblioteca Nacional del Perú Nº 2015-08108</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sferrazza Taibi, Pietro</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>La búsqueda de personas desaparecidas en Chile: ¿necesidad de un complemento humanitario?</title><secondary-title>Revista mexicana de ciencias políticas y sociales</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Revista mexicana de ciencias políticas y sociales</full-title></periodical><pages>79-108</pages><volume>66</volume><issue>243</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2021</year></dates><publisher>Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.22201/FCPYS.2448492XE.2021.243.70276</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Sferrazza Taibi - 2021 - La búsqueda de personas desaparecidas en Chile ¿necesidad de un complemento humanitario.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.scielo.org.mx/scielo.php?script=sci_arttext&amp;pid=S0185-19182021000300079&amp;lng=es&amp;nrm=iso&amp;tlng=es</url><url>http://www.scielo.org.mx/scielo.php?script=sci_abstract&amp;pid=S0185-19182021000300079&amp;lng=es&amp;nrm=iso&amp;tlng=es</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>La búsqueda de las víctimas de desapariciones forzadas es una problemática que ha generado una discusión profunda e interdisciplinaria. Al igual que otros países latinoamericanos, Chile está enfrentado a este problema, puesto que no se ha podido recuperar e identificar a la gran mayoría de las víctimas de las desapariciones cometidas en la dictadura de Augusto Pinochet desde 1973 hasta 1990. La presente investigación se cuestiona sobre el modelo de búsqueda ideal para enfrentar esta catástrofe. Asumiendo un enfoque sociojurídico, este artículo se adentra en las discusiones teóricas sobre los modelos de búsqueda, reflexiona sobre la manera en que la búsqueda se ha realizado en Chile desde la dictadura hasta el presente e intenta proponer algunos principios generales para la implementación de un modelo complementario que combine, coordine y conecte la persecución penal de los perpetradores por medio del proceso judicial y la búsqueda de las personas desaparecidas por la vía administrativa. A la luz de un contexto local, este artículo pretende aportar nuevas miradas al diálogo sobre la búsqueda &lt;/span&gt;que está desarrollándose en el marco de varias disciplinas de las ciencias sociales.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Report">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>CNRR</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Informe sobre calificación de víctimas de violaciones de derechos humanos y de la violencia política</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>1996</year></dates><pub-location>Chile</pub-location><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://CNRR - 1996 - Informe sobre calificación de víctimas de violaciones de derechos humanos y de la violencia política.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://acesse.dev/gRJk0</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Book Section">7</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>INDH</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Búsqueda de personas detenidas desaparecidas en el marco de la obligación de verdad y justicia</title><secondary-title>Informe anual situación de los Derechos Humanos en Chile</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Informe anual situación de los Derechos Humanos en Chile</full-title></periodical><pages>262-298</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2020</year></dates><pub-location>Santiago de Chile</pub-location><publisher>Instituto Nacional de Derechos Humanos</publisher><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://INDH - 2020 - Búsqueda de personas detenidas desaparecidas en el marco de la obligación de verdad y justicia.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://ia2020.indh.cl/informe/INFORME-INDH-2020.pdf</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Book Section">7</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>INDH</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Memoria y justicia: El pilar de justicia del proceso transicional post dictadura en Chile y el deber de perseguir, investigar, juzgar y sancionar las violaciones a los derechos humanos (1973 – 1990)</title><secondary-title>Informe anual situación de los Derechos Humanos en Chile</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Informe anual situación de los Derechos Humanos en Chile</full-title></periodical><pages>197-258</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2021</year></dates><pub-location>Santiago de Chile</pub-location><publisher>Instituto Nacional de Derechos Humanos</publisher><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://INDH - 2021 - Memoria y justicia El pilar de justicia del proceso transicional post dictadura en Chile y el deber de perseguir, invest.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Book Section">7</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Collins, Cath</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Vial, Tomás</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Verdad, justicia, reparación y memoria</title><secondary-title>Informe anual sobre Derechos Humanos en Chile</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Informe anual sobre Derechos Humanos en Chile</full-title></periodical><pages>27-98</pages><edition>Primera edición</edition><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><pub-location>Santiago de Chile</pub-location><publisher>Observatorio de DDHH - UDP</publisher><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Collins - 2017 - Verdad, justicia, reparación y memoria.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://derechoshumanos.udp.cl/cms/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/1-verdad-justicia-reparación-y-memoria.pdf</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Book Section">7</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Collins, Cath</author><author>Ordóñez, Andrea</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Vargas, Francisca</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Conversar con el pasado, transformar este presente: Justicia transicional como justicia constituyente</title><secondary-title>Informe anual sobre Derechos Humanos en Chile</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Informe anual sobre Derechos Humanos en Chile</full-title></periodical><pages>29-101</pages><edition>Primera edición</edition><keywords/><dates><year>2021</year></dates><pub-location>Santiago de Chile</pub-location><publisher>Centro de DDHH - UDP</publisher><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Collins, Ordóñez - 2021 - Conversar con el pasado, transformar este presente Justicia transicional como justicia constituyente.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>GTDFI</author></authors><secondary-authors><author>Dzumhur, Jasminka</author><author>Dulitzky, Ariel</author></secondary-authors></contributors><titles><title>Informe del Grupo de Trabajo sobre las Desapariciones Forzadas o Involuntarias: Misión a Chile</title><secondary-title>A/HRC/22/45/Add.1</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>A/HRC/22/45/Add.1</full-title></periodical><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><publisher>A/HRC/22/45/Add.1</publisher><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://GTDFI - 2013 - Informe del Grupo de Trabajo sobre las Desapariciones Forzadas o Involuntarias Misión a Chile.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://ap.ohchr.org/documents/dpage_s.aspx?si=A/HRC/22/45/Add.1</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sferrazza Taibi, Pietro</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>La definición de la desaparición forzada en el derecho internacional</title><secondary-title>Ius et Praxis</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Ius et Praxis</full-title></periodical><pages>131-194</pages><volume>25</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Crimes against humanity</keyword><keyword>Enforced disappearance</keyword><keyword>International Law of Human Rights</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2019</year></dates><publisher>Universidad de Talca</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.4067/S0718-00122019000100131</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Sferrazza Taibi - 2019 - La definición de la desaparición forzada en el derecho internacional.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.scielo.cl/scielo.php?script=sci_arttext&amp;pid=S0718-00122019000100131&amp;lng=es&amp;nrm=iso&amp;tlng=es</url><url>http://www.scielo.cl/scielo.php?script=sci_abstract&amp;pid=S0718-00122019000100131&amp;lng=es&amp;nrm=iso&amp;tlng=es</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This article analyzes the definition of enforced disappearance based on international human rights treaties specifically dedicated to this crime. Therefore, each one of the conceptual elements is identified and its content is explained considering the doctrine, jurisprudence and practice of international tribunals and bodies.</abstract></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Report">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>CPACDDEPVPPT</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Informe de la Comisión Presidencial Asesora para la Calificación de Detenidos Desaparecidos, Ejecutados Políticos y Víctimas de Prisión Política y Tortura</title></titles><periodical/><keywords><keyword>VALECH</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2011</year></dates><isbn>6.971.332-7</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.330.301-K</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://CPACDDEPVPPT - 2011 - Informe de la Comisión Presidencial Asesora para la Calificación de Detenidos Desaparecidos, Ejecutados Polí.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://bibliotecadigital.indh.cl/handle/123456789/600</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="My Collection.enl" path="My Collection.enl">My Collection.enl</database><ref-type name="Report">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>CNVR</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Informe de la Comisión Nacional de Verdad y Reconciliación</title></titles><periodical/><keywords><keyword>DERECHOS HUMANOS</keyword><keyword>DICTADURA - CHILE</keyword><keyword>RETTIG</keyword><keyword>VIOLACIONES MASIVAS Y SISTEMATICAS - CHILE</keyword></keywords><dates><year>1991</year></dates><isbn>9567419175</isbn><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://CNVR - 1991 - Informe de la Comisión Nacional de Verdad y Reconciliación.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://bibliotecadigital.indh.cl/handle/123456789/170</url></web-urls></urls></record></records></xml>
